

sonialahcene.com

linkedin.com/sonialahcene contact@sonialahcene.com +44 (0) 7977 693 635

I'm a passionate Digital Designer and Design Manager with lots of experience leading and delivering complex creative projects from conceptualisation to completion.

Very organised and self-motivated, I can work independently and also succeed in a collaborative and multidisciplinary work environment. I currently manage a team of Designers and Web Publishers looking after an eCommerce platform.



# LONDON, UK

Interested in remote opportunities



#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Web design

Creative direction

Project management

\_\_\_\_

Team management

eCommerce

•

Communications



#### **SKILLS & SOFTWARE**

Creative • Self-driven • Thorough

UX/UI • Illustration • Infographic • Branding • Image compositing

Photoshop • Illustrator • Adobe XD • Sketch • InDesign

HTML • CSS

AEM (Adobe Experience Manager) • JIRA • Confluence • Visual Studio Code

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### QVC UK, LONDON

In charge of the accurate and timely production of QVC's digital platforms, creating a seamless experience to millions of customers. My role as a Designer at QVC has quickly evolved into a more strategic position with increased responsibilities.

#### Digital Design Manager (2018 - Present)

- Leading the creative direction of digital content for the website and apps. Review and sign-off of all digital assets.
- Managing and developing a team of Digital Designers and Web Publishers. Coordinating and prioritising work. Recruiting and training new team members.
- Oversaw the launch of tablet and mobile apps: liaised with product owner in the US, established roadmap, defined best practices for content production.
- Implemented QVC new branding on digital platforms: created design guidelines and assets to improve user experience and consistency of digital platforms while allowing flexibility for the designers.
- Documenting processes and best practices in the team's wiki (AEM module guide, design workflows, onboarding guides, etc.).
- Helping improve workflow between the eCommerce and Design teams (JIRA training, improved briefs, best practices, etc.).
- Designing content for cross-channel campaigns and high-profile brands.

#### Lead Digital Designer (2017-2018)

- Designed and built major cross-platform digital campaigns (Christmas, Black Friday, Holiday Shop, etc.).
- Created UX documentation, photo briefs and assets used across all platforms and channels.
- Mentored other designers and led creative direction.
- Improved Design team's productivity by creating Photoshop templates.
- Streamlined work processes (new file naming convention, JIRA functionalities, etc.).
- Helped recruit new Designers and Publishers. Trained new team members.
- Deputised for the Design Manager until being promoted Manager.

# Digital Designer (2017)

- Created high-quality assets for the Home, Garden and Electronics departments
- Designed, built and published web pages in AEM.
- Elaborated conceptual briefs for the in-house photo studio.

#### SONIA L CREATION, LTD

#### Freelance Graphic Designer (2015-2017)

Offered graphic design and design consulting services for renowned brands and digital agencies.

- Key areas of expertise: graphic and digital design, illustration and design consulting.
- Brands and agencies: Timberland / GE / LinkedIn / Hootsuite / Brands2Life / The Story Lab / Mediablaze Group / Kaplan / Le Robert



# Digital Design Manager



#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor in Visual Arts (2012)

University Panthéon Sorbonne Paris, France Visual Art, History of Art, Philosophy of Art

# Master in Management (2007-2011)

EDHEC Business School Lille, France Focus in Marketing and Communications



#### **LANGUAGES**

English

French

Spanish

• • 0 0



#### **INTERESTS**

Baking baguettes

Doodling

Doing backflips on trampolines

#### LADBROKES, LONDON

# Web & Graphic Designer (2015-2016)

- Designed and built two Google Sites for the Security & Compliance and Enterprise Architecture teams.
- Developed the branding and visual identity of both projects.
- Designed merchandising items and communication materials.

#### ORANGE LABS UK, LONDON

#### Communications Executive (2012-2014)

- Responsible for the internal and external communication strategy.
- Developed new branding: logos, visual assets, communication materials.
- Designed and built Orange Labs' website (EZ Publish CMS).
- Created and managed Orange Labs' intranet using Wordpress (HTML/CSS).
- Designed merchandising items for events.

### LOUIS VUITTON, PARIS

#### Corporate Press Officer (2011)

- Organised a press trip for journalists from Korea, Hong Kong and Taiwan to visit Louis Vuitton's new luxury leather goods workshop in France.
- Supervised press kits production with in-house creatives and design agencies.
- Oversaw two press days and presented Louis Vuitton publications to journalists.
- Edited press reviews, gathered and analysed media alerts.
- Assisted PR officers on various projects and events.

#### ALLIANCE FRANÇAISE, WASHINGTON DC

#### Communication Assistant & Event Coordinator (2009-2010)

- Coordinated more than a hundred cultural events (screenings, concerts, theatre plays, festivals, etc.).
- Led a cross-promotion collaboration with the Corcoran Gallery in Washington DC.
- Maintained the website and designed promotional materials for events.
- Helped produce events by suggesting artists and negotiating their fees.
- Negotiated low rates for technical equipment and lodging for groups of artists.
- Produced reports on the trends and evolution of the cultural department (attendance, visibility, accounting).

#### VISIT MY WEBSITE

#### sonialahcene.com

